To our victory!
Thanks be to our ancestral spirits!
I knew about that ability Frost Pain has.
"Icy Burst," right? I understand
it can only be used three times per day.
Pretty well known.
Hmph.
Heh, yeah, but did you know
that Frost Pain has the power
to protect its user from cold?
It's not without its drawbacks, though.
That last ace up his sleeve
he played was that power.
He's an awesome warrior.
Yeah. I'm proud to call him my brother.
Rororo, you did well, too.
What do you think will happen now?
It could be that nothing has ended yet.
This "Great One" fellow
might come and attack us now.
So, is Zaryusu still asleep?
Probably, since he hasn't come out yet.
Crusch was pretty exhausted, as well.
We can let them rest for a while.
Ho... Well, maybe I'll go peek in on them.
This feast isn't gonna pick up
without its major players here.
Don't make too much
of a nuisance of yourself.
Hey, you guys at it?!
Guardians of each floor,
thank you for assembling before me.
We'll start with you, Victim.
This is your first time
meeting everyone else, isn't it?
Pleasure to meet all of you.
I am Victim.
I've called you, the guardian of
the eighth floor, for one reason--
we still have not identified
the foe who went after Shalltear.
We must consider that an as-yet
unforeseen incident may occur.
As such, we require a powerful skill
that is invoked by your death
to protect all of the guardians,
myself included.
I am sorry. I promise
to bring you back to life right away,
so I hope you'll forgive me.
Do not let it bother you, Lord Ains.
I was born in order to die.
If that power will be
of assistance to the Supreme One,
nothing could give me more joy.
One of the catchphrases
that Nazarick used goes like this--
"Greater love hath no man than this,
that he lay down his life for his friends."
It is truly an expression
that fits you perfectly.
I am grateful for your love.
Your words are more than I deserve.
Next up, Demiurge.
My lord?
First, allow me to honor you
for always answering my call.
What are you saying?
It is only to be expected
that I should report to you
at once when you call, Lord Ains.
Yes. It is evident that the sheepskin
parchment that you brought
can stand up to use in lower-tier scrolls.
Can I count on a stable supply of it?
Yes. That will not be a problem.
I have acquired an ample number of them.
I see. So, what was the name
of these beasts, again?
Beasts? Ah...
As they are two-legged sheep
from the holy kingdom,
how does the name "Abelion Sheep" sound?
Indeed. Sheep, huh?
So the beasts are actually chimeras--
or rather, a subspecies.
In Yggdrasil, chimeras had
the heads of a lion and a goat,
and their tails were snakes.
He must be trying to indicate
that a beast with a sheep mixed in
is something different.
I think goats would be better, but very well.
Continue what you are doing.
Now, as for you, Shalltear...
Y-Yes?
Regarding the splinter
you have in your soul...
Ah, Lord Ains, after being appointed
to the position of guardian,
and then doing what I did,
I ask you to please give me a punishment
worthy of a reprehensible fool
such as myself!
All right. I will settle on one later
and give it to you.
Lastly, Cocytus...
You ended in defeat.
Yes, my lord. I am terribly sorry
for my offense. I was--
Cocytus! If you're going to apologize,
lift up your face!
I beg your pardon.
Cocytus, tell me the reason
why you were beaten.
Right. I am very sorry for
losing the army you entrusted to me.
Not that.
Let me state upfront
that I don't intend to come down
on you too hard for this defeat.
The reason being that I don't care
who you are, everyone makes mistakes.
That goes for me, as well.
That being said, I ask you, Cocytus,
how could you have won?
I underestimated the Lizard Men.
I should have acted more cautiously.
Mm-hmm, that is correct.
You must never underestimate someone,
no matter how weak they are.
Is there anything else?
Yes. I think I may have had
insufficient information.
The enemy's strength, the topography--
I have learned that without
making sure of such considerations,
the chances of my victory were lowered,
no matter what I did.
Mm-hmm.
Not having enough commanders
was also a problem.
Since they were all lower-level undead,
I should have put in place
those who could issue orders as necessary.
Anything besides that?
I apologize, but that is
all I can think of right now.
Outstanding!
Except for that Elder Lich,
they were all spawn undead.
Their demise has absolutely
no effect on Nazarick.
Considering what one of
my guardians has learned from this,
I will be getting change back from this deal.
Thank you very much, Lord Ains.
Be that as it may,
the fact remains that you lost,
and you must be punished.
Cocytus! You will personally
mop up that sludge!
Exterminate the Lizard Men!
This time, without relying on anyone else.
A fantastic idea! Cocytus will expunge
his sin of being defeated,
along with all of the Lizard Men!
Lord Ains...
I have a request I would like to make.
I beg of you, Lord Ains...
You, who have brought defeat
to glorious Nazarick,
dare to petition Lord Ains?!
Remember where your place is!
--Cocytus--
--It's all right, Albedo.
Would you lift up your face, Cocytus,
and tell me what your request is?
Well, Cocytus? I simply
want to know what you're thinking,
and what you would like to say.
I am against killing all of the Lizard Men.
I beg you, show them mercy.
Cocytus, do you realize what you're saying?!
Albedo, do not get in the middle of this.
I beg your pardon. Please forgive me.
Now then, Cocytus, you must have
a pretty good reason for your request.
Something that will benefit
the Great Tomb of Nazarick.
Tell me what that is.
Yes, my lord.
There is a chance that valiant warriors
will appear among their number.
In my judgment,
it will be more beneficial to us
to have the Lizard Men
pledge loyalty to Nazarick,
and make them our subordinates.
That is indeed a convincing proposal.
If we were to use the Lizard Man
corpses to create undead,
they would only be of about the same level
as those from human corpses.
As such, there is no reason
to insist on Lizard Man corpses.
In that case...
However! It would be more cost-effective
to use undead created by me
than it would be
to leave the Lizard Men alive.
If there are any other benefits,
I'd like to hear them.
--Well, I...
--How about it, Cocytus?
If you have nothing more, than you won't
mind exterminating then, yes?
I see. That's too bad.
Lord Ains?
What is it, Demiurge?
My lord,
what if we were to use the Lizard Men
in a governability experiment?
Ho, now this sounds like
an interesting idea.
Yes. The time will likely come
when we will be handling
different races and powers.
I humbly submit that we ought to
perform an experiment in governing
in which we rule the Lizard Men's villages
by means other than fear
for when that time comes.
A terrific suggestion, Demiurge!
Thank you very much.
We will then accept Demiurge's proposal,
and shift from exterminating
the Lizard Men to occupying them.
Yes, my lord!
Demiurge, I'm impressed.
How can you say that, Lord Ains?
I am sure that you were already
aware of my modest proposal.
You were simply waiting
for Cocytus, were you not?
Hmph, you give me
too much credit. All I wanted...
...was for him to display some of his own
thinking, regardless of what it was.
Listen to me, guardians!
Orders are not things for you
to blindly obey and carry out.
You must mull them over
a little bit before you act!
Consider what will lead to
the greatest benefit for Nazarick!
Yes, my lord!
Now then, Cocytus, consequently,
your punishment must now be changed.
You will govern the Lizard Men,
and instill loyalty
toward Nazarick within them.
Rule through fear is forbidden.
As you wish.
I, Cocytus, promise to work hard enough
to measure up to the great mercy
you have shown me, Lord Ains.
All right, guardians,
I order you all to move out.
One team as a decoy, and another
to flaunt our power to the Lizard Men.
Albedo, make ready our soldiers.
Activate Gargantua, as well.
As you command.
Can I also assume that by sending a decoy,
you are considering that there is
someone who enjoys peeking at us,
and are giving the wrong impression
as to our true intentions?
That is correct.
Very good.
All right, everyone, time to get moving!
I'm grateful to you, Demiurge.
There's no need for that, Cocytus.
For you see, this is probably
the outcome that Lord Ains desired.
Huh?
You're saying that everything
is going according to Lord Ains' plan?
Leave it to Lord Ains!
B-But then, um, I mean, I'm just saying,
did he assume ahead of time
that Cocytus would lose?
Not so much lose, perhaps,
as he may have been entertaining
the idea that Cocytus would
probe the Lizard Men's strength,
and recommend whether or not
they could beat them.
That's Lord Ains for you!
He truly is beyond incredible!
It's fair to say that his assumption
of the role of coordinator for
the Supreme Ones was not just for show!
Wow, that was amazing! I didn't expect
Cocytus to say what he did.
In Yggdrasil, if you do anything
you don't have the skills for,
it's sure to end in failure.
But if he can gain tactics
and strategies from this experience,
that goes to prove that
we have the potential to grow.
But growth means change.
I can't even say that the absolute loyalty
of the guardians will never change.
Ah! That's scary stuff!
I wonder if there's anyone around
who can teach me kingcraft.
Now, it's about time
I got ready to move out.
Hmm?
There's a floral scent.
Have they sprinkled perfume on the bed?
Is this what wealthy people's beds are like?
If so, maybe I should keep that in mind
when pretending to be rich.
I had anticipated this,
but this is too soon.
Huh? It can't be.
I-Impossible.
Have you noticed it, too?
That is all magic equipment.
A mythical army.
What's with this cold wind?
This isn't possible.
The only thing that can
produce wind like this
is sixth tier magic or better--
"Control Weather."
Sixth tier?
This is the power
of the so-called "Great One"?
Remain calm!
Do not be intimidated, warriors!
Refrain from any actions
that would disappoint
the many ancestral spirits behind you!
What do you think?
They're making a move,
but they don't appear
to be preparing for battle.
What are they planning to do?
Hmm...
Is this the ruler of death?
What is that, exactly?
I don't know. I don't know what that is.
Everyone, hurry and get to higher ground!
We can be sure this is
the "Great One," all right.
Most likely.
I'm sold. From where that monster stands,
we might as well be dung.
Hmm?
What is that?
What is that thing?!
It can't be...
A royal procession?
We bring you the words of the Great One.
The Great One wishes to converse with you.
Let your delegate step forward at once.
Know that time that is wasted
is displeasing to the Great One.
H-He used all those monsters
simply for that?
Zaryusu...
My brother...
...will you come with me?
Mm-hmm.
Zaryusu...
Crusch,
I'll be back.
Be careful.
Thanks.
Considering their numbers,
they may think you going alone
to be disrespectful, Brother.
Besides, if we are killed
to make an example, I, as a traveler,
will not be missed in regard
to the unity of the tribes.
I am the representative
of the Lizard Men, Shasuryu Shasha!
And this is the mightiest
of the Lizard Men...
...Zaryusu Shasha!
Our master does not feel that
your posture is conducive to listening.
Demiurge?
Prostrate yourselves!
Do not resist!
Lord Ains, they have
adopted a listening posture.
Good work. Lift up their heads.
You are permitted to lift your heads!
I am the master of the Great Tomb
of Nazarick, Ains Ooal Gown.
First, I express my gratitude to you
for assisting with my experiment.
Now, onto the main subject.
You will fall under my rule.
Wha--?
However, it is likely...
...that you do not wish
to come under the rule of someone
against whom you have achieved victory.
Thus, in four hours, I will attack again.
The attacker will be one of
my trusted aides, Cocytus, on his own.
If you are able
to prevail against him, as well,
I promise to henceforth
leave you completely alone.
We surrender--
I would prefer you
not suggest something as tedious
as to surrender without fighting!
You're making an example of us?
I am done speaking. You have four hours.
Enjoy them while you can.
I ask that you wait! Will this ice melt?
Ah, that's right.
I simply did not want to
dirty myself with your mud.
I will dispel the effect of the magic later.
Farwell then, Lizard Men. Gate!
Goodbye, Lizard Men.
See you!
This is goodbye.
Um, er... well, please take care.
I bid you farewell.
You are free to move.
Do try to enjoy yourselves, Lizard Men.
Damn them!
This amounts to a ritual
sacrifice, doesn't it?
So, what do we do?
Call all of the warrior class
Lizard Men to arms.
In addition, we have those of us here--
Could I ask that it just be five of us?
Hmm?
If their goal is to demonstrate
their overwhelming power,
they are unlikely to kill us all.
If that's the case,
we will need a central figure
for the survivors to organize around.
A sound argument.
Mm-hmm. However, Zaryusu...
Why not? I agree with him.
Then that's what we'll do.
Crusch would be suitable.
Just a minute!
I'm going to fight, too!
Zaryusu, why would you
say such a thing at this point?
Because we've been given
a chance to survive.
Don't give me that!
Zaryusu, you convince her.
I'll see you again in four hours.
Crusch, please understand.
There's no way I can understand!
Besides, there's no guarantee we'll lose!
With my priestly powers, we might win!
I don't want to let
the female I'm in love with die.
Please grant the wish of this foolish male.
That's not fair...
I'm sorry.
You'll probably be killed.
--Yeah.
--And you're asking me to watch you die?
After we've become
so attached to each other?
Yeah.
I'm so happy that we met each other...
...but also, so sad.
Impregnate me!